Speaker: One invention that definitely improved the lives of millions of people
was the disposable nappy.
They were invented by a woman called Marion Donovan.
And now another invention which has made life easier.
The dishwasher was invented by a woman called Josephine Cochrane.
The car was invented by a man, but it was a woman, Mary Anderson,
who solved one of the biggest problems of driving.
On a trip to New York in 1903 Anderson noticed
that drivers had to open their windows
to see where they were going when it was raining.
Our fourth invention made life safer for people living in flats or apartments –
video entry phones.
They were invented in 1966 by Marie Van Brittan Brown.
And now an invention that has saved a lot of lives.
The modern life raft was invented by Maria Beasley in 1880.
Our last invention is one of today’s most important green technologies.
Mária Telkes, a Hungarian-American scientist, worked at the
Massachusetts Institute of Technology in the United States in the 1940s.
She was so interested in the power of the sun that her nickname was ‘the Sun Queen’.